1-day.com.au 2013-05-16

# Privacy Policy | One Day Privacy Policy Online | 1-day.com.au

back to help

1-day has put together the following privacy statement to display 1-days commitment to provide privacy. This document will display the policies 1-day has put in place to protect customers during information gathering practices.

**Use of your information**  
1-day **does not** sell or rent your personal information to third parties.  
We will only release account and other personal information if we believe release is appropriate to comply with law; facilitate court proceedings; enforce or apply our terms and conditions; or protect the rights, property, or safety of 1-day Limited, our users, or others.

**Email**  
It is the policy of 1-day to send our members emails throughout the purchasing process and other Newsletter emails they elect to receive. Further, it is our policy to immediately remove any member from any mailing list upon the member's request. In addition, 1-day will send out promotional material to its Newsletters subscribers promoting material related to 1-day.  
We do use email as a means of receiving feedback from our members, and we encourage you to email us with your questions or comments.

**Emailing Tools** 1-day provides tools on its web site to tell a friend about products, send vouchers and re-send order invoices. These tools must not be misused in any way to send spam or other content which would violate our privacy policy or Terms and Conditions.

**Spam**  
Occasionally we receive reports from some of our customers that they believe our email database has been compromised and we are leaking their email addresses to spammers. Some of these customers have set up an email address that is only used for our emails and they cannot understand why they are receiving spam emails as well.  
We have never and will never give out our customers email address or account details. We consider the practise to be both immoral and illegal. We are continuously monitoring our client database through our email service provider to ensure that it continues to be safe and secure..  
We continue to consult with a number of email service providers to ensure that we keep on top of this issue as it is very important to us. The best information we have received so far is that this spam is the result of a directory harvest attack. This is a common method employed by spammers to grow their databases for a future spam campaign. Directory harvest attacks combine a dictionary of common names (including first names, surnames, company names) with a list of domain names. The spammers then send emails to these addresses and logs any address that does not reply with a delivery failure (automated by recipients email server). [Click here](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Directory_harvest_attack) for more info...  
According to the Message Anti-Abuse Working Group, the amount of spam email accounts for between 88-91% of email messages sent during the last half of 2010. [Click here](http://www.maawg.org/email_metrics_report) for more info...  
We want to assure our customers that we will continue to monitor this area and take every step to ensure that their email addresses are not compromised or leaked.

**Discussion Tab Use** 1-day provides tools on its web site to add comments about a product on sale. These tools must not be misused in any way to post content which would violate our privacy policy or Terms and Conditions. 1-day reserves the right to remove any content which we believe isn't particularly helpful or appropriate. 1-day stores all comments in it's database to be used for internal research and administration.

**Membership Registration**  
Our site's registration form requires you to provide us contact information and may also require demographic information. Your contact information may be used to contact you when necessary.

**Updating Your Personal Information**  
1-day provides you with ways in which you can alter your personal data, including changing your email address, password, phone number, etc.

**Delivery Address Details**  
1-day enables you to save one delivery address which we will store against your profile. When you buy an item you have the option of entering a new delivery address which must be your own. And also the option to save this address to your profile.

**Control of Your Password**  
You are responsible for all actions taken with your user name, email address and password. Therefore we do not recommend that you disclose your 1-day password to any third parties. If you choose to share your user name, email address and password or your information with third parties, you are responsible for all actions taken with this information and therefore you should review that third party's privacy policy. Forgotten password emails will be sent to your accounts email address, it is your responsibility to protect this email account, 1-day assumes it will be secure when sending this email.

**Credit Card Security**  
We work diligently to protect the security of your personal information, including credit card information.  
Your credit card details do not get processed or transmitted through or via 1-days web site; all transactions are processed through a secure payment service provider. 1-day uses Direct Payment Solutions (DPS) to provide this service. DPS hosts and manages the payment page. All transaction sessions are stored and processed in encrypted strings.  
Your credit card details are not held by 1-day and cannot be accessed by 1-day staff. However they may be held by Direct Payment Solutions (DPS) ([review their Privacy Policy](http://www.paymentexpress.com/about/about_paymentexpress/privacy_policy.html)).

**1-day Vouchers** 1-day provides the facilities to present and redeem vouchers through the checkout system. Any voucher is to be used at the discretion of 1-day. 1-day also holds the right to terminate any Voucher which they believe is being misused.

**Voucher Terms and Conditions**

  * The Gift Voucher can be used only once. Any unused value associated with the Gift Voucher will be reissued with a new voucher code and will remain valid until the expiry date stated on the voucher.
  * If your order exceeds the amount of your Gift Voucher, you must pay for the balance with a credit card or other agreed forms of payment.
  * 1-day Gift Vouchers are not redeemable for cash.
  * 1-day Gift Vouchers are not refundable.
  * Valid up until the date recorded on the front of the Gift Voucher.
  * Recipients may only use 1-day Online Gift Vouchers for purchases online at [www.1-day.com.au](http://www.1-day.com.au/) or [www.1-daytee.com.au](http://www.1-daytee.com.au/).
  * The Gift Voucher will not be replaced if lost, stolen, or destroyed.
  * Each Gift Voucher is identified by individual code that must not be changed or copied by purchaser.
  * The purchaser is not allowed to transfer, re-assign, or re-sell Gift Voucher.

**Cookies**  
Cookies are small pieces of information that are stored in a browser-related file on your computer's hard drive when you use our web site. We use cookies to improve the user experience. Cookies are widely used on most major Web sites.

1-day mostly uses "session" cookies, which are removed from your computer 20min after you leave 1-day. A second cookie is placed on your computer (if you choose) for 1-day to remember you, this cookie is intended to remain forever. These are used so our web site can remember that you have logged in already and prevent you doing so more frequently.

**Other information we collect**  
We collect and use additional information to carry out internal research on our users' demographics, interests, and behaviour to better understand and serve you and our community. This information may include the URL that you just came from (whether this URL is on our site or not), which URL you next go to (whether this URL is on our site or not), what browser you are using, and your IP address.  
If you send us personal correspondence, such as emails, live chats or letters, or if other users or third parties send us correspondence about your activities or postings on the Site, we may collect such information into a file specific to you.

**Membership Removal**  
If you wish to have your registration removed from our directory for any reason, simply send us an email requesting to be removed.

**Access and removal of Information**  
You have the right to access, change and delete personal data that you provide 1-day as part of your subscription. You can exercise this right at any time by following the links in 1-day emails to our preference centre or please contact us.  
When you request changes to your 1-day subscription, it can take up to five days for changes to take effect.

**Updates to our information practices**  
From time to time, we make changes to our information practices or alter the functionality of our Web site. We always update this statement accordingly, so we encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on privacy practices at 1-day.

If you have any questions about our privacy policies or any other matter, please [contact us](http://www.torpedo7.com.au/contactUs.do).

1-day is a member of the [Torpedo7](http://www.torpedo7.com.au/contactUs.do) group of companies.
